# **RAUL RODRIGO**

Email: raul.rodrigo1984@outlook.com

**Skype:** raul.rodrigo1984

Mobile: +31 659 68 10 05

Address: Aalsmeerweg 5H 1059 AA Amsterdam

Nationality: Spanish

LinkedIn: http://nl.linkedin.com/in/raulrodrigo1984

#### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

I am a Master in Environmental Engineering and I have 5 years' experience in Quality and Environmental Management, focused on international standards, audits, energy, project management, sustainable development, commercial spirit and education. I also have fluent level of English in both writing and speaking with professional experience in this language. I consider myself a multi-task worker, dynamic, proactive, responsible, organized and analytic. My goal is to find a job related with my field which allows me to grow personal and professionally.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# SALES ASSOCIATE

Feb 2016- Present

#### TOURS AND TICKETS (AMSTERDAM, THE NETHERLANDS)

- Ensure high levels of customer satisfaction through excellent sales service.
- Assess customers' needs and provide assistance and information on product features.
- Remain knowledgeable on products offered and discuss available options.
- Cross-sell products.
- Team up with co-workers to ensure proper customer service.
- Build productive trust relationships with customers.

# ENVIRONMENTAL AND QUALITY SPECIALIST (Steel Factory)

Apr 2013-Dec 2015

### **GALLARDO GROUP S.L. (MADRID, SPAIN)**

- Specialist of quality and environmental management systems (ISO 14001, ISO 9001).
- Responsible for the annual audit plan (QEMS).
- Environmental monitoring operations based on EU and national legislation.
- Claim and complaints management.
- Contracting suppliers.
- Carbon footprint calculation.
- Supervisor of radioactive installation.
- Monitoring audits processes of rebar (Certificates valid for Spain, Portugal, Sweden and Denmark).

## **OHSE TRAINER**

Nov 2010 – Apr 2013

## **SANROMAN S.L. (MADRID, SPAIN)**

- Trainer e-learning, blended learning in QHSE.
- Teacher of Technical courses in renewable energy, energy efficiency, environment impact assessments, quality and environmental management.
- Creation of teaching aid (exercises, supplementary material, reading, tests...).
- Supervise learning contents.

#### **ENERGY AUDITOR**

Jun 2010- Nov 2010

# **ENERGIUM S.L. (MADRID, SPAIN)**

- Promotion of energy efficiency practices in municipalities and private companies creating audits by lighting and buildings.
- Engagement with key stakeholders of the projects.

## **EDUCATION**

MSc + BSc				
2010				

# Universidad Rey Juan Carlos I, Madrid, Spain

Bachelor + Master in Environmental Engineering (345 ECTS)

#### **FURTHER EDUCATION**

June 2015	Supervisor of Radioactive Installations
Feb 2013	■ Technical Sales Course
May-Sep 2012	<ul> <li>Audit and Certification of Efficiency Energy in Buildings and Industries</li> </ul>
Jan-Mar 2011	<ul> <li>Environmental Impact Assessment and Energy Efficiency</li> </ul>
Nov-Dec 2011	Environmental and Quality Management
Oct-Nov 2010	<ul> <li>Managing Health Security</li> </ul>

## LANGUAGES SKILLS

Spanish	Native	English	Fluent/Professional competence	
French	Basic competence	Portuguese	Basic competence	

## **COMPUTER SKILLS**

Advance User	•	MS Office Package: Word, Excel, Power Point
Intermediate User		Statistical program (spss) Software of Geographic Information System ( ArcGIS, ArcView)
Knowledge	•	SAP software

# INTERNATIONAL VOLUNTEER

August 2012	<ul> <li>Environmental volunteer work in Azores (Portugal): The high points in the program were the Organic Agriculture, Nature Conservation and Environmental Awareness</li> </ul>
Summer 2007	<ul> <li>Promotion of sustainable practices in waste treatment in Ciudad Colon (Costa Rica). Inventory of waste streams for the municipality of Colon, building programs. Empowerment local associations to promote the sustainable economic development of the low-income population of the community.</li> </ul>

# **HOBBIES**

- Travelling around the world, getting to know new cultures
- Sports: marathon runner, football player, hot yoga
- Spending time with my friends and family

# **REFERENCES**

On request